[{"question":"<p><strong>When literature recreates real events, it is said to be __________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Didactic","Factual","Fictitious","Allegorical"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When literature teaches moral lessons, it is said to be ______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Instructive","Informative","Didactic","Dynamic"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following is not a function of literature.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Inciting","Entertaining","Correcting","Exposing"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>As a medium for exposing and correcting ills in the society literature is ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Allegorical","Satirical","Political","Abusive"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Literature is referred to as a slice of life when it _____<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Recounts real event","Entertains its audience","Reveals reality in society","Accuses leaders of insensitiveness"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The time of the events in a literary text is referred to as __ setting<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Special","Spatial","Temporary","Temporal"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What distinguishes drama from other literary genres is that it is meant to be _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Read","Acted","Recited","Viewed"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The writer of a play text is referred to as ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Playwriter","Playwrite","Playright","Playwright"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The major divisions of a novel is called _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chapter","Stanza","Act","Scene"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The perspective from which the story in a novel is narrated is referred to as _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Angle","Focus","Technique","Point of view"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A misuse of a word in place of another one due to similarity in their sounds is known as _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Error","Parallelism","Malapropism","Mistake"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following is not a figure of speech.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Climax","Oxymoron","Antitheses","Mime"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following is not a figure of speech.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Climax","Oxymoron","Antitheses","Mime"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>_______&nbsp;is an indirect reference to an event, speech or action in the past.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Allusion","Exaggeration","Pun","Innuendo"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Use the poem below to answer question below<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Life is rise and fall<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>A tale of comings and goings<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The rhyme scheme of the poem is _______<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Of travails and doings<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>But death ends all<\/strong><\/p>","options":["aabb","aaba","abba","abab"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The central theme of the poem is_____&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Hope","Love","Faith","Vanity"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The tone of the poem is that of _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Resignation","Anger","Sorrow","Command"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The type of rhyme in lines 2 and 3 is ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alternate","Internal","Medial","Couplet"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Use the extract below to answer question below<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>William Shakespeare: <em>The Tempest<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Speaker A: The hou&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; s&nbsp; o&nbsp; come<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The very minute bids thee ope thine ear<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Obey, and be attentive. Canst thou remember<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>A time before we came unto this cell?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>I do not think thou canst, for then thou wast not<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Out three years old<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Speaker B: Certainly, Sir, I can!<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Who&nbsp; is&nbsp; speaker&nbsp; A?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alonso","Prospero","Antonio","Caliban"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Use the extract below to answer question below<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>William Shakespeare: <em>The Tempest<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Speaker A: The hou&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; s&nbsp; o&nbsp; come<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The very minute bids thee ope thine ear<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Obey, and be attentive. Canst thou remember<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>A time before we came unto this cell?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>I do not think thou canst, for then thou wast not<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Out three years old<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Speaker B: Certainly, Sir, I can!<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Who&nbsp; is&nbsp; speaker&nbsp; A?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alonso","Prospero","Antonio","Caliban"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Speaker B is _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ariel","Caliban","Andrian","Miranda"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The response of speaker B shows that speaker&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>A<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Underrates her memory","Dislikes her behavior","Understands her feelings","Approves of her carriage"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>_______<\/strong><strong>is the playwright of <em>Women of Owu<\/em>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Femi Osofisan","Wole Soyinka","Kobina Sekyi","Willam Golding"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One major theme in <em>Women of Owu<\/em> is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Hatred","Tolerance","Political bigotry","The folly of war"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In <em>Arms and the Man<\/em> Major Saranoff eventually marries_____<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Catherine","Raina","Nicola","Louka"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>______ is the playwright of <em>The Importance of Being Earnest.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Oscar Wide","Oscar Wild","Oscar Wilde","Oscar Wade"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>_________<\/strong><strong>misplaced Jack Worthing in a leader handbag.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cecily","Gwendolen","Mrs. Prism","Lady Bracknell"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of these characters in <em>The Importance of Being Earnest<\/em> is a clergy.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Algemon","Cardew","Brackell","Chasuble"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who is the author of <em>Lord of the Flies<\/em>?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Williams Shakespeare","Lord Baron","Williams Golding","Earnest Hemmingway"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A predominant theme in <em>Lord of the Flies<\/em> is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The innateness of evil","Religious fanaticism","Necessity for social order","The uselessness of adult"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which song is meant to lull a baby to sleep?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ballad","Lullaby","Dirge","Ode"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The last six lines of a patrachan sonnet is called ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Septet","Quatrain","Sextet","Octave"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A quatrain contains __ lines.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Five","Three","Four","Six"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>__&nbsp; is a moment of relief in a tragic play brought about through a comic scene.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong><br \/>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tragic relief","Comic relief","Suspense","Comedy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>is a device used to bring past event into focus to clarify present events in literature.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Prologue","Exposition","Foreshadowing","Flashback"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"}]